Christina Whethers

FULL STACK ENGINEER IN Amsterdam, NY

PHONE 518-248-2505 | EMAIL whetherschristina@yahoo.com GITHUB https://github.com/Flandolly | LINKEDIN https://www.linkedin.com/in/cwhethers/

SUMMARY

Software engineer with diverse knowledge in the many facets of full stack development, with the goal of providing an experience that goes beyond the simple delivery of a product, instead focusing on client acquisition and retention. Determined to create stunning, responsive and functional websites for companies who believe in and strive to prioritize the needs of the end user.

LANGUAGES	FRAMEWORKS		DATABASES	METHODOLOGIES
• Python	• ReactJS	• Bootstrap	• PostgreSQL	• Agile / Scrum
• JavaScript	• Express	• Django	• MongoDB	Object Oriented Programming
• HTML5/CSS3	• Node.js	 Mongoose 		• Version Control (Git/Github)
				• Wireframing
				• Test-Driven Development
				• RESTful APIs

PROJECT EXPERIENCE

General Assembly — Software Engineering Immersive Student Aug 2021 - Oct 2021

12-week, 420+ hour remote Software Engineering program focused on teaching principles of software development using a variety of technologies including Git/Github, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Node, SQL, Python and more. Developed a portfolio of individually and collaborative projects including:

- **TriviaMania**: A browser-sided game focused on testing users general knowledge on popular topics using pure JavaScript and HTML/CSS.
- PokeSearch: A wiki-style website that provides users a way to lookup Pokemon-related information
 utilizing a third-party RESTful API and built with React and React Router for site navigation. Designed
 responsively for different screen sizes, and future-proofed as the API is updated and expanded. Publicly
 deployed using Heroku.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Warehouse Systems Manager, Dollar General, Amsterdam NY, October 2020 – July 2021

- Oversaw and refined product pick locations, optimizing where necessary when product flow shifts
- Ensured products were located in proper zones and compliant with respective safety regulations
- Processed product moves if violations were found, reducing downtime by order selectors and truck drivers by over 10%
- **Collaborated** with receiving department to assign new products to their proper zones and keep the receiving dock **under 20%** occupancy
- Instructed new hires and cross trained colleagues from other departments to aid with daily operations
- **Boosted** building zone compliance **from 85% to 99%** over the course of three weeks.

Inventory Control Clerk, Dollar General, Amsterdam NY, May 2020 - July 2021

- Maintained accurate inventory throughout the warehouse including cycle counts and processing damaged inventory out of the system
- Researched high-value inventory discrepancies and relayed reports to supervisors and operational departments, reducing product X-outs by over 10%
- Operated manually invoicing stores when they were shipped an incorrect product or different amount of product than ordered
- **Processed** over 150 invoices per day during heavy product volumes
- Coordinated with peers to tackle problem areas where inaccuracies were common or frequent
- **Bolstered** warehouse to #1 in the network in terms of building inventory accuracy, totalling 89%
- **Lead** daily **start-up** meetings to overview department progress, remind **deadlines** and boost employee morale

EDUCATION

Fulton-Montgomery Community College, A.A.S. Computer Science — December 2019

GPA: 3.79/4